<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kurt Stubbings</title>
    <description>This is the portfolio website of Kurt Stubbings, a Digital Media Design  student at Bournemouth University. Avaliable to hire for work!
</description>
    <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://kurtstubbings.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 15:50:31 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 15:50:31 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Portfolio Website &amp; Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2016/02/rebirth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rebirth&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been here before, you may notice that something is different about this place…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again I’ve taken it upon myself to redesign my portfolio website as I was getting bored of the old design. I took this as an opportunity to try something a little bit different to my previous designs and as a chance to learn how to use Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously I had my main portfolio site as static content and had my blog under a directory and powered by Wordpress. However with this set up I found it too tedious to edit and update my portfolio and I Wordpress seemed a bit excessive for my needs. Using Jekyll is a great way to make portfolio management AND blog management much easier and to link them together in a static site, making it nice and speedy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sad news is that I’ve pretty much lost all of my old blog posts as my previous hosting got canceled before, and like an idiot I didn’t have a complete back up of my blog. This means that all of the written records of my work from first and second year have disappeared… for now. I’ll see what I can do to try and recover this information but don’t get your hopes up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news this site is still very much a work in progress. Still to come is a better design for this blog section, as I was lacking inspiration here, and some hopefully some fancy animations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/development/2016/02/08/new-portfolio-site/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/development/2016/02/08/new-portfolio-site/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Development</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
