<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kurt Stubbings</title>
    <description>This is the portfolio website of Kurt Stubbings, a Digital Media Design  student at Bournemouth University. Avaliable to hire for work!
</description>
    <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://kurtstubbings.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 12:29:47 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 12:29:47 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Finished Sculptures</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After a couple of weeks of cutting and gluing foamboard, the sculptures are finally finished. This now means its time to move onto the next phase of the project: developing the projections and working out how to set up the project for the exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-standing-sitting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full size standing and sitting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-standing-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full size standing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-standing-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full size standing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-standing-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full size standing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-sitting-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full size sitting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-sitting-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full size sitting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-sitting-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full size sitting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-lying-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full size lying&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-lying-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full size lying&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-lying-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full size lying&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wooden armature inside each of the standing and sitting models provides a more strength and stability than I anticipated. They can withstand being lightly pushed and wobbled without breaking which I was quite surprised by. At them moment the lying sculptures is in four unconnected parts: The baseboard, lower body, upper body, and one arm. This is so that it can be more easily moved when needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a slight issue at the moment that the standing and sitting models don’t fit through the doorway into my bedroom where there is a little more room for testing. As such, I’ve had to try to test them in the living room which is smaller. There isn’t enough room in the living room for me to project onto the standing man or more than one model so I’ve only done a quick test with the sitting model to see how it looked. In a dark room the effect was really impressive, like, &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; impressive. The projection is bright and striking and I can’t wait to see how it looks when across three full scale models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-sitting-glitched.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sitting glitched&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To &lt;em&gt;just about&lt;/em&gt; cover the sitting man, I needed ~3.25m between the front of the model and the projector. This will need to be even further to cover the standing model. I am hoping that I’ll be able to mount the projectors on the ceiling and that this might help with my coverage issue, but I will need to check with the uni if this is feasible and then test it to see if it is actually an improvement. My other idea is to have the projector on its side at 90 degrees so the height is the larger dimension, but at the moment I don’t have a method of securely positioning the projector in this way so it will have to wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have come to the realisation that this isn’t going to be possible with a single projector. My current hope is to be able to do it with two projectors, but it may require three. This is my next main focus and I am currently working on procuring a space large enough for me to be able to test with the full scale models. I will also need to consider health and safety as I need to ensure the projectors and protruding cables don’t becomes hazards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this doesn’t mean I’m completely stuck in the meantime. I’m still working on my glitch projections and coming up with ideas to try. I came up a lists of goals and ideas as a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make it appear as though these physical sculptures/ objects are glitching or malfunctioning in a digital way&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Must invoke the uncanny&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blurs the boundaries between real and simulated, physical and digital&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ideas&quot;&gt;Ideas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep it simple with using just glitch effects and having parts of the sculptures seemingly disappear/ change colour/ etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The level of glitch could change based on external factors. Or there could be a number of different ‘scenes’ with different styles of glitch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use face tracking to put the viewers face on the sculptures then glitch/ distort them sculptures and faces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Distorted body parts (eyes, hands, feet, etc.) could glitch into appearance. This could perhaps be interactive in a way for example using sound monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/04/30/finished-sculptures/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/04/30/finished-sculptures/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Physical Work Begins!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Following on from my last post, I jumped in to designing my full scale models so that I can begin building them. For this, as usual, I used Cinema4D so that I can model them to the exact dimensions I need and be able to see how they will look in relation to each other and at the correct scale. With some help, I gathered some measurements of myself, to use along side my reference images so that I could make sure I was designing at the right dimensions. From here I used some of my previous models for inspiration and got to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started with the standing model by trying to work out how I wanted the torso and legs, then adding the arms in the final iteration. For my other two, the designs didn’t change much from my 1/8 scale models as these forms were really well received by my peers and I loved them too. The only adjustments were to the sizings and proportions as I changed them to better fit within my measurements. After coming up with my three forms I showed them to a few of my peers for feedback, made a few minor adjustments, then it was time to begin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In regards to my last post about materials, I’ve spoken to a local supplier for MDF and they won’t be able to cut my sizes as many of them are too small for their machine. I’ve also contacted a supplier of balsa wood blocks, and they too can’t cut the pieces I need to size due to the limitations of their machine and the sheer cost of balsa wood. The MDF suppliers suggested that I could contact a local workman they knew, but implied that it wouldn’t be cheap and would take quite a while as I needed a lot of cuts so I had to some up with another plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having had a long discussion with one of my tutors, Liam, we’ve come to the conclusion that foamboard might actually be the best option for my case. Given my incredibly limited access to tools, foamboard works well as it is easy to cut and can be assebled with hot glue as I’ve been doing for my smaller models. Another benefit is that if I were to make a mistake or it was to get broken, it should, in theory, be easy to repair as long as I have some spare materials at hand. To negate the concerns I had about the strength of the models if they were made of foam board, we decided that creating an internal structure to build around would add the strength needed - more about this later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing that I was going to use foamboard, I set about generating my cutting list. The three models in total use 61 boxes. Each box requires 6 sides. That’s a grand total of 366 pieces of foamboard I am going to need. Knowing that the foamboard is 5mm thick, I had to account for this when coming up with my measurements. I devised a wonderful naming scheme for this too. Each sculptures was named either A, B or C. Then each box was numbered, and then each of the three different pairs of sides was named a, b or c, meaning I could easily tell how they were to be constructed. So I made a list. I checked it twice. I didn’t find out who was naughty or nice, but I did luckily find a couple of mistakes so that made it worth the effort. The grand total was 114 unique dimensions. This is going to be a joy to cut…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/measurements.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Measurements&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/standing-variants.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Standing variants&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/all-three-angled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;All three models&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/cutting-list.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cutting-list&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so, back to the internal structures. Liam and I knocked up a quick test with some scrap materials to see how it would work. The results of this are pictured below. In short I am going to have a large base board, a few up-rights, and a few blocks to just make it sturdy. I think I will give each sculpture the same sized base board so that it creates congruence between the models and visually makes them more linked. For the standing model, the support system will be simple, just a base and an upright. The lying is even simpler, just a board which I can glue the model onto. Finally the sitting which is the one we mocked up. For this I’m going to use a weird Tetris block shape and then I will build the foamboard blocks around this structure to bury it inside. This structure will definitely give it the extra strength needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dad suggested a way of strengthening the foamboard boxes too. I am going to the edges together, and when that dries I will run glue up the inside seam to make them more rigid. Also for certain, larger boxes I can add an internal support out of foamboard so that there is some more strength in the middle and not just around the edges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the successful test, I went away and mocked up the supported in Cinema4D so I could better visualise the dimensions I need and how they will go in the sculptures. For both the sitting and standing sculptures, I am planning on running the supports up the left legs as I can’t run them up the centre due to gaps in the design. Luckily, due to the disjointed, abstracted form, there is some leeway with how the boxes are placed, therefore I can made adjustments around the internal structure if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have ordered some foamboard which is going to be delivered next week, and I am planning on visiting B&amp;amp;Q to buy the wood needed for the support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/support-test-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Support test&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/support-test-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Support test&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/support-test-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Support test&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/standing-with-support-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Standing model&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/standing-with-support.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Standing model&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/sitting-with-support.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sitting model&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/sitting-with-support-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sitting model&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/lying-with-support.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lying model&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/03/26/physical-works-begin/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/03/26/physical-works-begin/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Progress Update - Physical Work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I came up with my concept of the uncanny and presented it to my tutor and peers to get some feedback. Luckily the idea went down a treat which means I can sleep a bit easier at night and not stress about coming up with a concept. This part has been the most challenging so far as we haven’t been trained in art or art history so it is quite far out of the norm of what we’re used to. However the next challenge, will probably be even harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I have my direction, I can begin with the arduous task of designing and somehow actually building the sculptures. Up to this point, I’ve just been building scale models out of foamboard. However from working with foamboard, I’m having doubts about its strength when it comes to full size models. Well, I think  it would be suitable for the lying sculpture, and perhaps even the sitting sculpture but for the standing I don’t think it will work as the foamboard isn’t strong enough, and I’d like all three (preferably) to be made of the same material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sculptures are large, and there’s three of them, therefore I need to find a material which is strong but low cost. I also really need something that is easy to work with as I am quite poorly equipped for building physical works at the moment. I have spoken to the technicians in the sci-tech workshops however they’re unable to provide me any space or access to the tools as they’re needed for people on scitech courses (which is entirely reasonable). This leaves me in quite a difficult position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a few ideas so far on how I could do it. The best two at the moment are using either MDF or balsa wood. MDF would work well as it is low cost and easy to work with (if I had the tools). The biggest issue here is getting the MDF cut to size as I am going to need A LOT of rectangle cut. Even then I would need to assemble and clamp them to make the blocks needed. The other alternative is balsa as it is very lightweight, relatively low cost (not as low as MDF) and easy to work with. I have found a few places online which sell it in blocks. I could therefore design the sculptures around the dimensions of these blocks and do it this way. But this will definitely be far more expensive, and even I may need to resize the blocks, make them smaller, or combine them to make them larger and will need to assemble them to make the models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another of the many issues is transportation. These are going to be big, Kurt-sized models and not the easiest things to transport. in my assembly I will need to take this into consideration and perhaps build in a way to take them apart and assemble them on site. This is something I will need to think more about later but it is definitely worth considering now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may have guessed, this is going to be the most difficult part of this project and has been concerning me the most. when working with the digital we take for granted the ability to constantly edit and change things - not a luxury had when working with physical objects. I am going to need to check and double check my dimensions when cutting the material as I can’t afford to make mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/03/20/progress-update/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/03/20/progress-update/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Uncanny</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a continuation of the thoughts at the end of the &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/graduate%20project/2017/03/11/mini-models/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; on the uncanny as a concept for my project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon further reading and thinking, it becomes clear that the uncanny relies on personal experience, so is not clearly definable. So as I see my project as being uncanny, it doesn’t mean that others will see it in this way - but I suppose its impossible to cater for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freud and Jentsch both argue that the animation of inanimate objects is uncanny, and occurs when the boundary between animate and inanimate objects becomes confused. For example when objects imitate life, blurring the cultural, psychological and material boundaries between life and death. This explains the uncanniness of zombies and ghosts. But I don’t believe that it had to be about life and death, it can be blurring different boundaries, say physical and digital? Real and simulated? I suppose this is why humanoid robots are quite uncanny (You know the creepy Japanese ones with skin and terrifying expressions). All of this leads back to my idea of glitchy sculptures being uncanny. The glitch brings the calm, motionless sculptures to life in a very chaotic and confusing fashion. It blurs the boundaries between digital and physical media and makes us question the reality of what is before us. On a deeper level, as previously mentioned, it blurs the boundary between the real and simulated in how the sculpture is &lt;em&gt;appearing to&lt;/em&gt; glitch, but also in the fact that the glitches themselves are simulated (but the audience shouldn’t know this).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stumbled across some somewhat similar work by New Media artist, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hellocatfood.com/uncanny-valley/, Uncanny Valley&quot;&gt;Antonio Roberts&lt;/a&gt; which he did as part of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://inhabitingthehack.github.io/&quot;&gt;Uncanny Valley event&lt;/a&gt; in 2015. In short, his work involved projecting glitch art onto natural objects, exploring the interaction between the projection and the uneven surfaces. What I find the most interesting about this is the vibrant, digital looking colours contrasted with the natural forms and textures. It raises questions about the nature of and interaction between the physical and digital, which can be quite uncanny and uncomfortable. I’ve included a couple of photos taken from Roberts’ Flickr from the event, so credit goes to him for those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/roberts1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Uncanny Valley&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/roberts2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Uncanny Valley&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/03/12/the-uncanny/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/03/12/the-uncanny/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Face Capture</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After discussion my minor breakthrough yesterday, it was suggested that I try adding in some face capture to enhance the uncanny effect. I set up a quick and dirty test again and gave it a go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of the work is done in VDMX again, using a plugin which handles face capture (how convenient). For this I just used the webcam on my laptop and this plugin, then set the output of the plugin to syphon out so that I could use it as an input in MadMapper. From here I created four new quads and mapped them onto the face areas of the miniature sculptures. I also added a mask to the input as straight out of madmapper the video is a rectangle which includes some background so I crudely masked it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This test was more just a proof of concept, just to see if I could do it - turns out I can. However, without some major optimisation I’m not sure this is going to be possible given my current computing situation. As you might be able to see in the taskbar of the image below, my CPU was running at 99 degrees… and that really isn’t okay. Even more so, looking at the processes, VDMX combined with madmapper was using around 400% of the CPU. Now I’m now mathematician bit im pretty sure thats more than 100%. As a result, I’m not comfortable with leaving my computer running like this for extended periods of time, as it is likely to cause some damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the brightside there are some easy improvements to be made as, I didn’t really take much care while putting together this prototype (I wanted it done as fast as possible). Firstly I can optimise the videos, both in terms of resolution and the codec used. At the moment the video for each of the sculptures is aproximately 720p, but given their shape and size, it’s pretty unnecessary. Also, when projecting glitchy things having a high resolution isn’t essential, the low-res pixellated look can just add to the ‘glitchy aesthetic’. Also I was using MPEG-4 codec for the videos as this renders out quickly and has a low file size. I’ve read that it is recommended to use photojpeg or Apple Intermediary codecs as they are less resource intensive when used in VDMX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/face-capture-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;VDMX and MadMapper&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/face-capture-still.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Face Capture Still&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a short video with some footage from the test. I reused some of my existing glitchy footage and just had the captured face overlaying it. On this small scale it is difficult to encounter any added uncanniness, but with some imagination the effect could be visualised. In hindsight, I think it would be worth glitching the face too, see what effect that would have. I imagine at full scale it would look quite impressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I was to continue chasing this idea (after fixing obvious optimisation issues of course), there are a few things I will need to consider. Firstly it is the placement of the camera and lighting. For the projection to look most impressive I need a dark room, but for the camera to detect faces I need light. Also I need the camera to be in front of the sculptures so that it can detect the faces of audience members looking at the sculptures so the positioning will need to be considered. Also, again, the poses of the sculptures comes under consideration. Perhaps it could be interesting to have the standing sculpture pointing towards where the camera is (or even secretly holding the camera) so that once it captures the face of the viewer the work suddenly changes and the viewer is now pointing at themselves. While this is happening, we have two onlookers (assuming keeping the tripartite installation) who also exhibit the viewers face. So we have the viewer watching the viewer point at themselves - quite an experience. All this while glitching and distorting, resulting in some wild, confusing, uncanny encounter. I will also need to think how best the glitches can ehance the uncanny experience when taking the face capturing into consideration. This can only come from more experimentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find this idea really interesting but I am apprehensive due to technological limitations. It is an interesting way of adding interactivity to the work by forcing the viewer to be a part of it. They give no consent to having their face stolen, they just happen to be standing in the right place at the right time and the project works it’s magic. It is something that is unexpected when encountering sculpture in a gallery context, which is traditionally a very passive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed//6QtHgZAjJ1s&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/03/12/face-capture/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/03/12/face-capture/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mini Models</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After deciding on wanting three models for the installation, I thought it was about time to start doing some tests with some scale models and experiment with different glitch projections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step involved getting some source images to work from of myself. With the help of a friend, I frolicked around for a little bit as they took pictures of me in different poses giving me a starting point for modelling. This process was inspired by the way Gormley operated, using his own body for his sculptural works. From here I then took some measurements of myself, did some quick maths to work out scale sizes and sketched up some ideas. These are shown below. I have no idea what most of these numbers mean anymore but at least it provides evidence of… something. For the mini models im working at 1/8 scale so that they’re around 22cm tall. Using the measurements I took, I started designing a couple of models in Cinema4D at the correct scale, This allowed me to visualise better how they would look before moving to physical materials. It also gave me the dimensions I needed to quickly and easily cut out the foamboard and glue it together - Each one still took over 5 hours to make though! You may have noticed that the standing model has a different ‘aesthetic’ to the other two - this is because I reused one of the scale models I had built before as I didn’t want to delay progressing by another day to build yet ANOTHER scale model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/model-source.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Selection of some of the source photos taken&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/model-maths.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Some measurements and sketches&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/mini-model-c4d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Models mocked up in Cinema4D&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The arrangement of the models in this scaled version is rather arbitrary, I just placed them in a way that seemed acceptable to project onto with a single projector and cover a sufficient amount of the surfaces to make it look cool. Ideally in the real model I’d like to be able to project directly downwards onto the sculpture, inviting people to come closer and view the projection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mapping onto this was kind of a nightmare. With such complex shapes, it’s quite a task to perfectly map onto them so I had to settle for some rather crude mapping with quite a lot of bleeds - thank God this is just a prototype. I built a VDMX layout so that I could work with the different sculptures and easily be able to customise the projection for each one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/model-vdmx.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;VDMX Layout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a long time setting up, I was finally able to start projecting some different ideas. I’ve made a quick compilation video to show some of the different types. It’s worth noting that this is very difficult to film as the camera on my phone struggles with the crazy flashing lights. Below is a commentary about each test to share what the idea was and my thoughts on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed//zxk8Lp8GGSw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standard glitching:&lt;/strong&gt; This one was the logical starting point moving from a singular sculpture to a three. The Glitch has the same settings across each model, but with a different seed so that the exact glitch pattern isn’t the same. While it looks alright, it doesn’t seem to have any depth or meaning, it’s a bit dull in the grand scheme of things.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standard glitching plus:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a slight variation on the first clip, but with the addition of the Glitch FBO effect in VDMX to the lying sculpture. This effect basically mangles data from the graphics card resulting in some wild, fast and crazy glitch effects. I changed how the mapping works a little for this one so that the projection from the lying sculpture can slightly interfere with the other two - it doesn’t come across very well in the video but it totally does it. The idea for this one was associated with freud’s notion of the id as the unconscious mind and primal desires. I imagine this being rapid, quickly changing, chaotic.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RGB:&lt;/strong&gt; This idea is inspired by the red, green and blue colour separation of displays (and by the cones in our eyes). It separates the three colours, one to each sculpture and then just adds some glitchy effects to it for good measure. I think this idea has some potential but I’ll need to rationalise the colour separation, and better utilise it to communicate something.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dark sculptures:&lt;/strong&gt; In pretty much all of my tests prior, I started with some base colour projection, usually white, then add the glitch to that. This meant that the sculptures were always lit and bright. In this idea, only the glitches introduce bright, fast, colourful flashes of light which are chaotic and disorientating. Unfortunately I had to film it in quite a bright room as my camera couldn’t handle the sudden changes in light levels very well, but I assure you it looks very good in a dimly lit room. Scaled up, I can imagine this effect being quite incredible as the sculptures fleetingly flash into life and disappear and instant later. If the room was dark enough it would be difficult to take in the sculptures as a whole, instead they would be interpreted through brief fragments as they show themselves then disappear back into the darkness. This idea definitely has potential (especially as I really like it).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nature imagery:&lt;/strong&gt; This idea is inspired by discussions had with my tutor and peers. For it I chose some nature videos from YouTube pretty much from random, just to test the appearance of projecting imagery onto the sculptures rather than simply ‘glitch’. I then glitched them in VDMX. The result was quite interesting. The glitchy videos were very chaotic which I found entertaining and hypnotic. Having them constantly glitch meant that it was quite difficult to comprehend what the imagery was of. Plus the shape of the sculptures themselves don’t really commend themselves as canvases for watching 16:9 video content.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audio-reactive nature imagery:&lt;/strong&gt; Because I could, I made the glitches audio-reactive so that they would turn on and off and change intensity based on audio detection. This is just an example of a potential interaction method, as I would like to add interactivity to the project if it can help get a message across. Having the glitch controlled by mused created a sense of purpose or intent for the glitch, as it if had some more solid meaning for being there.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main issue with these last two examples is the introduction of imagery/ video content projected onto the sculptures. Doing so, for me at least, distracts from the fact that they’re sculptures at all. They’re shaped like people, they’re formidable and have a sense of presence. I think this takes it too far from being a sculpture in the traditional sense. Sculptures are motionless, eternal figures which solidify a moment in time and tears itself from its bounds. I want it to look as if the sculptures themselves are glitching, not the content projected onto the sculptures glitching, which is why im apprehensive to add specific imagery. Sculptures don’t glitch. BUT these ones are. They are physical objects seemingly malfunctioning in a digital way. Yet these sculptures are not digital, how is this possible? The combination of glitch and sculpture breaks down the boundaries between the physical and digital worlds. It allows us to see a digital phenomenon more physically, and in a way, something a physical phenomenon more digitally. This idea fits nicely with the paradigm shift in how we consume the majority of our media and art. It breaks from how we usually experience sculptural works. Sculptures are still, calm, serene, but these ones are confusing, chaotic, yet mesmerising. The eternal beauty and stillness of the sculpture is rudely interrupted by bright flashes of colour, fragments seemingly disappearing and reappearing, all in a way which goes beyond our established relationship with sculpture. For me, it breaks the traditional awe associated with physical art and creates something slightly uncomfortable because the fleeting moments of digital chaotic beauty are almost impossible to catch. The beauty is not so much in the form of the sculpture but in the glitch moments, the moments you may never encounter again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now you may be thinking: Why are the sculptures people? Why not different trees or something? Well, while writing that last paragraph I had an idea. Using the human form for the sculptures makes them more relatable. They may be abstracted, and expressionless combinations of white boxes, but they serve as a blank canvas for projecting ones self. In my case especially, as these sculptures are modeled on my dimensions I can only imagine the effect will be rather &lt;em&gt;uncanny&lt;/em&gt;. Having these three Kurt-sized models staring back at me should be quite an experience. The sculptures are strangely familiar. The variety of poses (standing, sitting and lying) makes them more human, more relatable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this brings us to my idea. &lt;strong&gt;The uncanny&lt;/strong&gt;. In an amazing stroke of luck, it brings us back to our good friend, Sigmund Freud, the starting point for the investigation with his work on the human psyche. The uncanny is a psychological concept which describes something that is strangely familiar and foreign such that it creates a feeling of discomfort. It can create a sort of cognitive dissonance due to being attracted to yet repulsed by an object, in this case, the glitching sculptures. Uncanniness was first explored by Ernst Jentsch who described it as a product of ‘intellectual uncertainty’ caused by something which is not fully understood. For me, the digital fits this perfectly, especially when it malfunctions or glitches. Its something most of us encounter on a daily basis, yet in a way it has remained rather mysterious. These magical boxes which light up and allow us to access unlimited amounts of information instantly. Unfortunately the ubiquity of the digital has normalised this, but if I just sit and think, it just astounds me and makes me feel quite uncomfortable. Freud developed the concept of the uncanny, specifically an aspect of the word derived from German etymology. Uncanny comes from the German word &lt;em&gt;unheimlich&lt;/em&gt; which applies to things which were intended to remain secret, hidden away, but have come into the open. Sound familiar? In my previous writings I’ve mentioned how glitches serve as breaks in the usual or expected flows of information. They reveal the computational nature of the digital which exists outside of our representations. Glitches unmask the veil of the screen, revealing the true nature of the software behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re seeing something in a broken or malfunctioning state. I can only really talk for myself, but I don’t usually like broken things. I like things to be precise, perfect, but there is something about glitches which are strangely enticing and beautiful. They’re chaotic and confusing, seemingly beyond my control, yet the flashes of colour in all their distorted glory mesmerise me. This point can be linked back to an argument Frued made about the uncanny. The uncanny is what unconsciously reminds us of our own id, our forbidden and unconscious desires. This is perceived as threatening by our superego. The items and people we project our repressed impulses upon become uncanny threats. For example zombies are uncanny. They’re humanlike, but they’re dead and they eat people. We find zombies uncanny because they’re so almost human but we don’t want to be associated with them. It could also be to do with our fear of death, and perhaps some people’s repressed desires to eat other people. So could the uncanny appeal of glitch be playing on people’s fear of being broken, or being seen in a way that reveals our hidden thoughts and desires? Maybe…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put simply, seeing human shaped sculptures glitch is uncanny. It’s taken me a while to realise what was so interesting about it and I think I’ve finally worked it out. They’re sculptures, sculptures don’t glitch. They’re people, people don’t glitch. Yet here we are. It’s weird. It’s uncomfortable. It’s uncanny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little side note about any arguments one might have to do with me talking about glitch as being a result computational error -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of glitches used in the work thus far are simulations. Theyre generated using a tool which allows for so much freedom in recreating the glitch aesthetic its amazing. This allows me to fine-tune the glitch projected onto the sculptures but they’re still chaotic, random and beautiful. However from the perspective of the audience, they (generally) don’t know that it is a simulation, so they will perceive them as real glitches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the effects used in VDMX does, in a way, result in real glitch. It works by distorting data taken from the graphics card resulting in actual glitches. This, when combined with my simulated glitches disrupts the boundary between real and simulated to the point that no one has any idea whats going on anymore. However this effect needs to be used sparingly as it, due to its nature, can result in crashes - which is not what I want.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/03/11/mini-models/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/03/11/mini-models/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Artistic Development</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The past few weeks have been spent trying to ‘find enlightenment’ and come up with some creative and original ideas to develop this project further. The focus of this thinking has been on finding a way to make the sculptural forms themselves more meaningful. Following a meeting with my tutor to discuss possible directions, the beginnings of a concept began to emerge which will be explored in the coming week before solidifying the idea and putting it into production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work is to be presented at a triptych of three sculptural forms, each with a projection mapped component. I want to have the forms in different poses: lying, sitting, and standing, representing the three parts of the psyche suggested in Freud’s structural model. As with the psyche, these three parts work together to form a singular whole, in the work the forms and their glitches will be interrelated contributing to a singular entity representing the mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The analogy also fits in line with ideas from cognitive psychology and viewing the individual as a process of information, much like a computer. The environment provides data which is transformed by the senses. This information is then processed and can be stored, retrieved, and transformed using ‘mental programs’ which results in a behavioural response. In general we selectively attend to a singular activity, and ignore other stimulation. This is because humans have a limited processing capability. So what would happen if we were to overload this processing capability? Would it result in a glitch like in a computer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently my challenge is integrating these ideas with digital media, and in particular how glitch art would fit into this model and compliment the chosen poses for the forms. Here’s a short summary of my current thinking and understanding:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;id&quot;&gt;Id&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The id operates with the unconscious part of the mind. It is primitive, instinctual, illogical and irrational. It operates on the pleasure principle that every impulse should be satisfied immediately and does not change over time or with experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me the lying pose is the most suggestive of this. It implies sleeping or dreaming, when the unconscious mind is able to operate (mostly) free from external stimuli. Sleep is a basic, primal instinct and is unavoidable. Digitally I am imagining something fast paced to be projected, symbolising the impulsive and illogical side of the mind. How would glitches operate here? Would there even be glitches? Perhaps when basic instincts conflict, this could be a glitch. Such as when you’re drifting off to sleep then you’re sudden twitched awake as the brain panics for some reason (I have no idea why this happens…).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ego&quot;&gt;Ego&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ego is the part of the id which has been modified and influenced by the external world. It mediates between the unrealistic and irrational id and the external real world. It is integral to decision making and finds realistic ways to satisfy the demands of the id. The ego is rational, realistic and orientated towards problem solving by testing reality to find solutions - enabling people to demonstrate self-control and tame the id. However it has no concept of right or wrong, it only aims to gain pleasure without causing harm to the self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is more difficult to pin a pose on. On the one hand it fits well with sitting, as it is the logical intermediary step between lying and standing. But equally it could be standing as that pose is implicit of action, or going somewhere, which fits with the drive of the ego as it seeks to pleasure and fulfil the id’s wishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;superego&quot;&gt;Superego&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly there is the superego which incorporates the values and morals of society learned from others. It controls the id’s impulses which are forbidden by culture and society and persuades the ego towards more moralistic goals rather than simple realistic ones. The superego consists of the conscience and the ideal self. The ideal self is an imaginary picture of how one ought to be such as career aspirations, how to treat others and how to behave properly as a member of society. Falling short of the ideal self results in guilt, whereas behaving in line with it or social norms is rewarded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one I am also finding difficult to associate with a pose. Initially I thought it could be standing, as standing is the pose in which we often interact with society and our environment. Standing can be quite confident and it had a sense of ‘presence’ to it as if this standing figure IS the ideal self, standing tall and proud - what one should aspire to be. But I also think it fits with sitting. As it is a slightly less active pose than standing, it is suggestive of stopping and taking a moment to think. It could be analogous to the mind pondering the moral implications of an action desired by the id. However in this case, sitting doesn’t suggest the power that the superego has to control both the ego and the id which standing does as an authoritarian pose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;beep boop&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/02/22/artistic-development/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/02/22/artistic-development/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Form Experiments</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After creating my first prototype, I drew up a couple of alternate form ideas just to explore shapes and possibilities. This lead to the creation of two 1/8 scale models using the offcuts of foamboard to better visualise these forms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took measurements of my body to try and get the proportions right as I’d like to use myself for the forms - similar to how Gormley works. In future I’ll need to find a volunteer to take pictures of me in various poses and from different angles so I have better reference material for abstracting my form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/02/scale-sketches.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Form sketches&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/02/form-experiments.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Form experiments&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/02/08/form-experiments/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/02/08/form-experiments/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prototype One</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For my first prototype I looked at a range of Gormley sculptures to be inspired by their form. From here I moved into Cinema4D to create a scale 3D model of what I wanted to build to try it out. I want the models be the same height as me and the 3D model made reflects this. As this is a prototype I made it at 1/2 scale to save on material. The physical model was made out of 5mm foam board which was glued together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this stage my focus is on the physical models as this is the part which will be the most difficult for me in the project. I am also trying to construct a decent workflow for this so I can setup and get the project running as quickly and easily as possible. At the moment I am using After Effects to render some glitchy videos, then placing those into VDMX. I’m using VDMX so that I could potentially add interactivity in the future and also distort the videos further making them look more glitchy. I then syphon out to Madmapper and then map it onto the model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;current-challenges&quot;&gt;Current Challenges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Every time I move the projector or model I have to re-map and mask the image all over again. I don’t think this is avoidable but I need to find out if I can do it faster.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Originally I planned to have the projector mounted on the ceiling, however having these sculptures mapped right down to the floor I don’t think this is feasible (and I can’t test ceiling mounting in my bedroom). In the future I will need to experiment with projector placement&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foamboard is quite expensive and I don’t think it has the structural integrity to withstand being a full kurt-sized model. I will need to find a new material I can use for the models which are sturdier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How could I experiment further with the form?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What if the boxes were at different angles rather than all forward facing?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Could I add texture or use different materials to explore the effects?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/01/prototype-1-C4D.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Prototype one made in Cinema4D&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/01/prototype-1-model.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Prototype one half scale model&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/01/prototype-1-VDMX.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;VDMX Project&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/01/prototype-1-madmapper.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mapping in Madmapper&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/01/prototype-1-mapped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Final mapped model&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/01/14/prototype-one/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/01/14/prototype-one/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Graduate Project Start</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With the dissertation out of the way and the foundation research and dossier complete, its now time to begin the arduous task of making my graduate project idea a reality. This blog will act as a place to chart my explorations and findings as I continue to develop/ hone my idea and eventually realise the project for the end exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this section in the blog is to chart the development of my project from the initual pitch until the exhibition. It is a place to for me to organise my thoughts and feelings and express this as the work evolves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project I proposed is titled “Gormley to Glitch” and is a projection mapping installation. The idea was to combine sculptural forms inspired by the works of Antony Gormley with glitch art to explore the physicality of the digital medium. The dossier mapping the development of this work can be found &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/01/kurt-stubbings-dossier.pdf&quot;&gt;here (4.5mb)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge now is to develop this further: shifting away from a reliance on Gormley towards something more original, creative and unique. As I lack any formal training in fine art, this part will be the most difficult. It will requre coming up with ideas which are less linear, less predictable. I need to take a step sideways (perhaps into another dimension) not forward. In the coming weeks I plan to try and find this inspiration from within, avoiding conventional sources of inspiration to come up with something original.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/01/08/graduate-project-start/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/01/08/graduate-project-start/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
