<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kurt Stubbings</title>
    <description>This is the portfolio website of Kurt Stubbings, a Digital Media Design  student at Bournemouth University. Avaliable to hire for work!
</description>
    <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://kurtstubbings.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 10:32:52 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 10:32:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Artistic Development</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The past few weeks have been spent trying to ‘find enlightenment’ and come up with some creative and original ideas to develop this project further. The focus of this thinking has been on finding a way to make the sculptural forms themselves more meaningful. Following a meeting with my tutor to discuss possible directions, the beginnings of a concept began to emerge which will be explored in the coming week before solidifying the idea and putting it into production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work is to be presented at a triptych of three sculptural forms, each with a projection mapped component. I want to have the forms in different poses: lying, sitting, and standing, representing the three parts of the psyche suggested in Freud’s structural model. As with the psyche, these three parts work together to form a singular whole, in the work the forms and their glitches will be interrelated contributing to a singular entity representing the mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The analogy also fits in line with ideas from cognitive psychology and viewing the individual as a process of information, much like a computer. The environment provides data which is transformed by the senses. This information is then processed and can be stored, retrieved, and transformed using ‘mental programs’ which results in a behavioural response. In general we selectively attend to a singular activity, and ignore other stimulation. This is because humans have a limited processing capability. So what would happen if we were to overload this processing capability? Would it result in a glitch like in a computer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently my challenge is integrating these ideas with digital media, and in particular how glitch art would fit into this model and compliment the chosen poses for the forms. Here’s a short summary of my current thinking and understanding:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;id&quot;&gt;Id&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The id operates with the unconscious part of the mind. It is primitive, instinctual, illogical and irrational. It operates on the pleasure principle that every impulse should be satisfied immediately and does not change over time or with experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me the lying pose is the most suggestive of this. It implies sleeping or dreaming, when the unconscious mind is able to operate (mostly) free from external stimuli. Sleep is a basic, primal instinct and is unavoidable. Digitally I am imagining something fast paced to be projected, symbolising the impulsive and illogical side of the mind. How would glitches operate here? Would there even be glitches? Perhaps when basic instincts conflict, this could be a glitch. Such as when you’re drifting off to sleep then you’re sudden twitched awake as the brain panics for some reason (I have no idea why this happens…).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ego&quot;&gt;Ego&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ego is the part of the id which has been modified and influenced by the external world. It mediates between the unrealistic and irrational id and the external real world. It is integral to decision making and finds realistic ways to satisfy the demands of the id. The ego is rational, realistic and orientated towards problem solving by testing reality to find solutions - enabling people to demonstrate self-control and tame the id. However it has no concept of right or wrong, it only aims to gain pleasure without causing harm to the self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is more difficult to pin a pose on. On the one hand it fits well with sitting, as it is the logical intermediary step between lying and standing. But equally it could be standing as that pose is implicit of action, or going somewhere, which fits with the drive of the ego as it seeks to pleasure and fulfil the id’s wishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;superego&quot;&gt;Superego&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly there is the superego which incorporates the values and morals of society learned from others. It controls the id’s imposles which are forbidden by culture and society and persuades the ego towards more moralistic goals rather than simple realistic ones. The superego consists of the conscience and the ideal self. The ideal self is an imaginary picture of how one ought to be such as career aspirations, how to treat others and how to behave properly as a member of society. Falling short of the ideal self results in guilt, whereas behaving in line with it or social norms is rewarded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one I am also finding difficult to associate with a pose. Initially I thought it could be standing, as standing is the pose in which we often interact with society and our environment. Standing can be quite confident and it had a sense of ‘presence’ to it as if this standing figure IS the ideal self, standing tall and proud - what one should aspire to be. But I also think it fits with sitting. As it is a slightly less active pose than standing, it is suggestive of stopping and taking a moment to think. It could be analogous to the mind pondering the moral implications of an action desired by the id. However in this case, sitting doesn’t suggest the power that the superego has to control both the ego and the id which standing does as an authoritarian pose.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/02/22/artistic-development/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/02/22/artistic-development/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Form Experiments</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After creating my first prototype, I drew up a couple of alternate form ideas just to explore shapes and possibilities. This lead to the creation of two 1/8 scale models using the offcuts of foamboard to better visualise these forms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took measurements of my body to try and get the proportions right as I’d like to use myself for the forms - similar to how Gormley works. In future I’ll need to find a volunteer to take pictures of me in various poses and from different angles so I have better reference material for abstracting my form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/02/scale-sketches.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Form sketches&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/02/form-experiments.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Form experiments&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/02/08/form-experiments/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/02/08/form-experiments/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prototype One</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For my first prototype I looked at a range of Gormley sculptures to be inspired by their form. From here I moved into Cinema 4D to create a scale 3D model of what I wanted to built to try it out. I want the models be the same height as me and the 3D model made reflects this. As this is a prototype I made it at 1/2 scale to save on material. The physical model was made out of 5mm foam board which was glued together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this stage my focus is on the physical models as this is the part which will be the most difficult for me in the project. I am also trying to construct a decent workflow for this so I can setup and get the project running as quickly and easily as possible. At the moment I am using After Effects to render some glitchy videos, then placing those into VDMX. I’m using VDMX so that I could potentially add interactivity in the future and also distort the videos further making them look more glitchy. I then syphon out to Madmapper and then map it onto the model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;current-challanges&quot;&gt;Current Challanges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Every time I move the projector or model I have to re-map and mask the image all over again. I don’t think this is avoidable but I need to find out if I can do it faster.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Originally I planned to have the projector mounted on the ceiling, however having these sculptures mapped right down to the floor I dont think this is feasible (and I can’t test ceiling mounting in my bedroom). In the future I will need to experiment with projector placement&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foamboard is quite expensive and I dont think it has the structural integrity to withstand being a full kurt-sized model. I will need to find a new material I can use for the models which are sturdier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How could I experiment further with the form?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What would happen if the boxes were missing their front faces and the projector shon into the hollow space?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What if the boxes were at different angles rather than all forward facing?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Could I add texture or use different materials to explore the effects?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/01/prototype-1-C4D.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Prototype one made in Cinema4D&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/01/prototype-1-model.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Prototype one half scale model&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/01/prototype-1-VDMX.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;VDMX Project&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/01/prototype-1-madmapper.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mapping in Madmapper&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/01/prototype-1-mapped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Final mapped model&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/01/14/prototype-one/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/01/14/prototype-one/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Graduate Project Start</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With the dissertation out of the way and the foundation research and dossier complete, its now time to begin the arduous task of making my graduate project idea a reality. This blog will act as a place to chart my explorations and findings as I continue to develop/ hone my idea and eventually realise the project for the end exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this section in the blog is to chart the development of my project from the initual pitch until the exhibition. It is a place to for me to organise my thoughts and feelings and express this as the work evolves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project I proposed is titled “Gormley to Glitch” and is a projection mapping installation. The idea was to combine sculptural forms inspired by the works of Antony Gormley with glitch art to explore the physicality of the digital medium. The dossier mapping the development of this work can be found &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/01/kurt-stubbings-dossier.pdf&quot;&gt;here (4.5mb)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge now is to develop this further: shifting away from a reliance on Gormley towards something more original, creative and unique. As I lack any formal training in fine art, this part will be the most difficult. It will requre coming up with ideas which are less linear, less predictable. I need to take a step sideways (perhaps into another dimension) not forward. In the coming weeks I plan to try and find this inspiration from within, avoiding conventional sources of inspiration to come up with something original.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/01/08/graduate-project-start/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/01/08/graduate-project-start/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Portfolio Website &amp; Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been here before, you may notice that something is different about this place…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again I’ve taken it upon myself to redesign my portfolio website as I was getting bored of the old design. I took this as an opportunity to try something a little bit different to my previous designs and as a chance to learn how to use Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously I had my main portfolio site as static content and had my blog under a directory and powered by Wordpress. However with this set up I found it too tedious to edit and update my portfolio and I Wordpress seemed a bit excessive for my needs. Using Jekyll is a great way to make portfolio management AND blog management much easier and to link them together in a static site, making it nice and speedy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sad news is that I’ve pretty much lost all of my old blog posts as my previous hosting got canceled before, and like an idiot I didn’t have a complete back up of my blog. This means that all of the written records of my work from first and second year have disappeared… for now. I’ll see what I can do to try and recover this information but don’t get your hopes up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news this site is still very much a work in progress. Still to come is a better design for this blog section, as I was lacking inspiration here, and some hopefully some fancy animations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/development/2016/02/08/new-portfolio-site/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/development/2016/02/08/new-portfolio-site/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Development</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
