<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kurt Stubbings</title>
    <description>This is the portfolio website of Kurt Stubbings, a Digital Media Design  student at Bournemouth University. Avaliable to hire for work!
</description>
    <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://kurtstubbings.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 11:26:53 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 11:26:53 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Glitch Style Refinement</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After recieving some feedback on my previous tests and coming up with a few more techniques to try, I went back to resume testing! Again, the notes below are mostly for my reference but feel free to read them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YJMt1AlAjQQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style 7 - Bigger displacement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This style is a development from style 3 which disables the small glitches and makes the large displacement glitches even bigger. I kept them quite infrequent and made them even slower as was suggested. The higher degree of displacement works better I feel, however I think some of the glitches are too slow, they seem almost too permanent to be glitches. It doesn’t really have the same psychological effect as a real glitch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style 7.5 - Displacement with occasional colour&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A variation of style 7 which uses small glitches for the majority, but had a 25% chance of displaying a large glitch which will introduce colour. It is still slower, but perhaps slightly more varied. Very similar to style 7, the colour glitches are quite infrequent but they not really impactful enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style 8 - Feedback loop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I found a way to create a feedback loop with layers so that there is constant iteration of effects being applied over and over resulting in some really glitchy results. I used this effect alongside the Glitch FBO and a zooming effect, triggering both randomly and independantly. The zoom effect is controlled by audio analysis to determine how much to zoom. I definitely think using the FBO effect is important for making something which actually looks glitched. It adds a lot more depth, chaos and complexity to the projection which is missing from the standard After Effects renders. Also being able to trigger it on and off dynamically is a huge bonus. The feedback zooming loop is also quite interesting actually as the zooming in and out dynamically creates a greater sense of depth to the models, emphasising their 3D-ness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style 9 - Glitch plus me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is based on feedback from my tutor to use the human figure more holistically. This style has an image of me mapped onto each of them which appears behind the glitchy sculpture so that when the sculpture glitches I appear, how lovely. The result was quite interesting, and definitely made them feel more like people. The glitching and shifting fragments revealed a hidden side of the sculpture - as they were modelled on my form. This version could do with more glitch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style 9.5 - Glitch plus me + Glitch FBO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As the title suggests, the Glitch FBO effect is back. This time it is definitely more effective with its glitchiness. Couple of things worth noting though. The FBO effect often causes the layer to not be displaying fully, therefore when i’m revealed I don’t display all the time either. It might be worth separating me into a separate layer and exploring that. Also with the FBO effect added, I need to consider the frequency of me appearing. I want to to be frequent enough that people notice it and understand it, but not so frequent that it becomes mundane and undermines what the glitch is about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style 10 - Glitch plus me glitching&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Similar to style 9 but this time I’m also glitching occasionally when revealed. This is definitely an improvement on style 9 as it adds more dynacism to the underlying me, makes it more interesting and revealing I think.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style 10.5 Glitch plus me glitching + Chaos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adding the feedback glitches from Style 8 to this really spiced it up. It has a fantastic balance between calm and chaos while still occasionally reveling what lies underneath. I like this one as it is less obvious that the person appears as sometimes the glitches take it beyond reality. The models go through a variety of forms, from static sculpture to slightly distorted, revealing the human form underneath to pure digital, colourful chaos which may have brief glimpeses of the human form. Its as if one level of glitch reveals whats underlying on the first layer, then it goes deeper, too deep beyind our representations of the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style 11 - Separated glitch layers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is a continuation of the previous styles but the images of me are in an independant layer so the effects can be controlled differently. The Kurt layer is just using displacement glitches so It doesn’t end up too distorted but there is still a degree of distortion. The sculpture layer has a mixture of glitches with Glitch FBO effect included occasionally to add some spice. I think having me on a separate layer is a definite improvement as i’m more persistantly underneath when revealed by the FBO effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style 11.5 - Separated layers + feedback&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Again using the wonderful feedback effect with the zooming on top of style 11 to add more glitch. This effect I think adds more ‘spectacle’ rather than psychological depth but it sure does look cool. I found this style one that I could look at for longer as it was far more interesting to watch because there was more happening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;general-comments-from-myself&quot;&gt;General comments from myself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I quite like the simple displacement effects with no added colour, especially how they disregard the existing blocky form and break in other places, not just where the distinct blocks are.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If I go with the option of including fully body images of myself, I will need to take more consideration of what clothes I wear and facial expression I have to make it more meaningful. I would also line it up better but as this was for a test it didn’t seem worth the hassle. Perhaps I could also have different outfits or expressions which change… who knows.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My current struggle is to find a balance between pretty pictures and considering the actual psychological effect of glitch art. Currently I’ve been focused on pretty pictures and just creating a chaotic, colourful spectacle. As much as I love this, my supervisor has a valid point that I need to further consider the artistic value of what I create. This more challenging for me as I am very technology focused. I’m more interested in the tools and how theyre used rather than deeper meaning within the work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;feedback&quot;&gt;Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/06/11/glitch-style-refinement/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/06/11/glitch-style-refinement/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Another Day, Another Glitch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Day two of testing on the full scene. Today’s plan was to create a few different styles which I could potentailly use as presets, then get some feedback on them so they can be improved and development. Testing was done using one minute loops played back at around half speed to reduce the framerate for both performance and aesthetic reasons (so the glitches aren’t as fast).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7gPavFbe4f0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style 1 - Glitching all three together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On my first day of testing I appled glitch effects to the individual models. This time I wanted to try glitching all three together. The benefit of this is that fragmenets of one model can appear on the others. However in reality it doesn’t look very good when they all glitch similarly at the same time. It looks choreographed and mundane, not as glitchy as i’d like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style 2 - Colourful compression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This test goes back to glitching the models individually but adds in some compression with the saturated colours. Each one has a different level of compression and a slightly different frequency of glitch (20%, 25% and 30%). The compression makes the edges look pixellated, however after watching it for a while it seems a bit pointless to do this with the projection. The models themselves already look compressed and pixelated, doing the same to the projection just makes it look like its been mapped poorly. I think compression might be something to exclude from projections as the form of the models already does enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style 3 - Just displacement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This style of glitch doesn’t introduce any colour to the sculptures. Each one had displacement glitches only with slight different settings to add some more variety. I quite like this effect. Its subtle but still really interesting. With each sculpture occasionally glitching and at different times, it sort of makes you think ‘did that really just happen?’ then you try and catch the next glitch as sometimes the one you’re looking at doesn’t do anything. It would be interesting to add some colour into this occasionally too, as as variant to the style with constant colour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style 3.5 - Just displacement + Glitch FBO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using the same source video as style 3, this one has random use of the Glitch FBO effect too to add further distortion. I like how it adds in occasional displacement which is huge so that a whole model is unlit, and how it adds in some crazy distorted colours and patterns. It makes it actually look far glitchier and more interesting, though it might be worth using the FBO effect more sparingly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style 4 - Displacement with a splash of colour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The video for this started similarly to style 3 however throughout the minute long loop, it is occasionally set to use colour in the glitches alongside the displacement. This adds some variety as sometimes it’ll do nothing, sometimes it’ll glitch and just displace and others it’ll displace and change colour. I think this works well as a style as there is more variety.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style 4.5 - Displacement with a splash of colour + Glitch FBO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Similar to how style 3.5 works, this one uses style 4 with occasional Glitch FBO. I slowed down the randomiser for this one so there are sometimes longer periods without the excessive glitching which I think is an improvement. This is probably my favourite style so far as it’s the most visually interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style 5 - Displacement + Convergence effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I decided to have a look through at some of the other effects in VDMX and found one called Convergence which seems to chaotically move the colour channels and blend them. I used the style 4 video as a base and had the effect randomly turn on and off. This style is surprisingly captivating. I’m not sure if its becuase its something new and I’m so used to the Glitch FBO effect, but I’m a big fan of this one and it definitely has a potential use in the final project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style 5.5 - Displacement + Convergence effect + Glitch FBO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Again, similar to style 5 with the adducution of the Glitch FBO effect for further distorted, glitchy wonderfulness. The two effects run on different randomisers so theres such a variety to look at ranging from no glitch at all to full displacement and both effects at once. I think this could cut it as my new favourite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style 5.5.5 - Displacement + Convergence effect + Glitch FBO + Face capture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is an iteration of style 5.5 which adds face tracking into the mix. Well for the video its not live face tracking as its only me in the room and I cant film and be in front of the camera. BUT it would work live, as long as the lighting in the exhibition room allowed for it. The faces are behind the glitched imaged in the mapping which use the add blend mode. So when the glitched video is white, the face cannot be seen, but when it is anything but white, the face can come through. As it is the glitches which make the video not white, the face appears when its glitched which is a very interesting and entertaining effect. The biggest issue with this is that its very resource intesive and makes my laptop run about 15 degrees hotter than it does without it. However in the show I think I might be able to work around this when I have an iMac to use. The plan for the show is to run VDMX on my laptop, then use syphon to get it to the iMac which is running madmapper and the 2 projectors. Depending on how powerful the iMac is, I could also run a face tracking Processing sketch and use syphon again to get that into madmapper. If I did it in Processing I could even have it display multiple faces so if theres more than one person they all get involved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style 6 - Complete Chaos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This final style is similar to 5.5.5 but uses a different source video. The origial glitched source video has quite large blocks of colour in it which are a lot bolder than previous iterations. While this style looks quite nice, it doesn’t live up to the glory of styles with extra effects. So I added the random Convergence effect and Glitch FBO effect as well as the face tracking which makes it a lot more lively and interesting to watch. I also added the FBO effect to the face itself so that it glitches independantly too which works really well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;feedback&quot;&gt;Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few comments from friends and family after showing them the above video. The nested bullets note my commentary on the feedback:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ones with the faces look the best&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The face doesn’t have to be in the same place, it could move from block to block or something.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is a great idea, though at the moment i’m not yet sure how to implement it.s&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It would go great with music (but I understand that isn’t what the project is about)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Maybe not music, but I have done audio reactivity so I could possibly control the glitches with ambient noise levels.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There should be more blacked out pieces which look like they’re missing
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This could be done by making the displacement values higher.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Style 6 works really well becuase of the colours and the faces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Style 3 is also interesting due to the simplicity, makes it seem more ‘real’ as pieces of the sculptures are removed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perhaps try mixing style 3 with style 6 to get a good balance of both - Add long pauses of cut outs like in style 3
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I will definitely try something like this, I can slow down the glitches even further to enhance the effect&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The first few styles are better as when it gets too flashy it can be hard to focus on whats going on
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is an interesting comment as most other people prefer the chaotic ones. I think it would be good to include a variety of styles in my presets ranging from mildly glitchy up to crazy glitchy chaos.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tutors-comments&quot;&gt;Tutor’s comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glitch happens when the illusion of reality breaks down by an electronic disturbance that wakes the viewer up and reminds them that they are looking not at reality but a “construct”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What you have at the moment is not really doing that. It is more decorative than disturbing and that’s a problem.. I think that you might need to shoot some video which is closer to the structures themselves and then create animations in which they unravel, split open or rupture or are disturbed in some way that momentarily undermines or opens up their structural integrity.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I agree with this point. I have gotten a bit carried away with creating ‘glitch spectacle’ focusing on finding something which looks cool rather than considering the deeper meaning. As for creating certain animations, I will definitely give it a go (its on my to-do list in fact!). Its worth noting however that I am somewhat limited in the complexity of animations I can create as when I relocate to the exhibition space next Monday and set everything up, I’ll have to recreate all of the content again which there may not be enough time for more complicated effects. This is why I’ve been exploring a few of the real-time effects I can use so they can be changed and played with on the fly.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The actual figures are configured in a rather flat way. They need to operate against each other somehow operating more in space.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;My current placement for the sculptures and projectors is to try and take up as little space as possible so I can be considerate in the actual exhibition. I agree with you that there should be more depth and they could do with being spaced apart a little more. I’m currently using a layout which has a smallish footprint and I can project onto the most surfaces. Once we’re into the exhibition space I’ll be able to see how much I can spread and and better determine where exactly each model goes for optimal effect.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your background in the exhibition space will be important. It should obviously be black or white but maybe work with panels operating at different angles.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is something that depends on my placement in the exhibition space, so i’ll cross that bridge when i can. Admittedly in my current testing space it’s not ideal having a sofa behind the models!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Currently when you do include a body part it is just a face you should maybe work with more holistically with the human form.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It is currently just a face as I had the idea of doing live face tracking for it so that members of the audience will become part of the work. I’ve written a Processing sketch that will detect up to three faces and can display them, one on each model (faces are used multiple times if there are less of them).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I have an idea which I will attempt today. I’m going to get someone to take some pictures of me which I can line up on each of the models so that they could ‘glitch’ into placement occasionally - hopefully I can do this.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maybe you need to re-visit some of your earlier experiments from last semester with the classical bust
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I think what worked really well with the classical bust is that firstly its far more realistic than my models, so the glitchy aesthetic seems more out of place. It might also be due to the classical bust being more recognisable, more iconic, something that you really wouldn’t expect to be glitching as you’re already familiar with it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/06/10/another-day-another-glitch/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/06/10/another-day-another-glitch/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bringing The Family Together</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After many weeks of waiting, I am finally able to test the project fully with all three models together. I now have the opertinity to try out different layouts and styles to see how the final project will look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step one involved chosing an arrangement for three models and the 2 projectors. The goal was to get the best coverage on the models but taking up the least space as I need to be considerate of other people’s projects at the show. I am hoping that I’ll be able to use a corner at the exhibiton as it will block off 2 possible directions people could come from. At the moment I have the sitting and standing models staggered at the back and the lying model in front of them. The distance between and taken up by the models and projects is quite large, but I’m hoping this isn’t an issue in the exhibition space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/06/space-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The space&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the exhibiton space allows I’d like to spread it out a bit more, so that it isn’t so compressed but I’ll find out if I can do this in a week or so. I also need to be conscious that the sitting and standing models are using the same projector so they can’t be too far from each other or at too different depths or the projections wont be in focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my current layout, there are two possible viewing angles which work well: one face on and another from the side which lets the audience see one side and the front. The viewing is split by the placement of the projectors so I will need to make sure that no one will knock or jog them as it will ruin the mapping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this testing, I am using my old Macbook and a Dualhead2go so that I can run two projectors off a single output. However the Dualhead2go the uni has isn’t the version that is compatable with mac so it doesn’t work as well as it should. it SHOULD output a double wide video  (2 * 1920px x 1080px) and then each projector uses half of that, but as this one isn’t supported, it only puts out a single width video and spreads it across the two. This means each projector is actually running at 960px x 1080px which is a weird resolution. In the show this shouldn’t be an issue as I am planning on borrowing a mac from the uni which as two video outputs anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4XXLta6xic0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the video there are three main variations, each shows from the two viewing angles. The first variant is one of the standard glitch aesthetics I’ve been using as I really like it. The sculptures are constantly lit and there are coloured fragmenets jumping about the place. The second introduces the Glitch FBO effect from VDMX which is randomly tuned on and off. This results in moments which are REALLY glitchy and is far more chaotic. Having the effect turn on and off randomly allows for some great contrast between stillness and utter glitchy chaos. The final variant builds on the second and thows in some eyes during the extra glitchy moments as they’re controlled in the same way. This was more interesting than expected and I plan on working out a good scale and amount of eyes/ other features to use for the show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As there are so many different glitchy styles and aesthetics, my current plan is to create a series of loops which will cycle through and repeat throughout the exhibiton. So instead of it being 5 hours straight of a single effect, I could great some 5 minute loops for example and play through them. I think this will make it more interesting for an extended period of time as there is more variation. The next step is to come up with the loops!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/06/09/bringing-the-family-together/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/06/09/bringing-the-family-together/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Random Thoughts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is a collection of paragraphs and random thoughts which probably don’t make much sense but I had to write them down to document my thoughts and feelings at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of my ideas about glitch have been about bringing the familiarity of the digital into the physical world. They have been centred around an exploration of the digital medium itself and exploring its properties. Ideas about compression, bandwidth, and glitches to name a few are all ideas most of us understand to an extent when it comes to interacting with the digital. However these are not things that make much sense in the physical world. For example we can compress an image and it can become pixelated, or artefacts might appear on the image as a result of the compression and the file format used.  These are things which ‘make sense’ when viewed on a screen, but bringing it into the material world gets a bit confusing. This is something James Bridle has been trying to explain with his notion of the New Aesthetic, as the boundary between the physical and digital becomes blurred and indistinct. We are seeing digital artefacts in the physical world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this is where my project and ideas come into play. We see the new aesthetic everywhere these days in consumer media and products. We are even seeing it in art with glitch art and new media art (which glitch art and my project probably fits under) as it infiltrates all aspects of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gormley To glitch is focused on Antony Gormley inspired sculpture and Glitch art; the clue is in the name. However I’m coming to realise that I’ve been neglecting other aspects of digital media in my exploration. There are aspects of digital video and digital projection which I have largely overlooked for some reason. There are things like RGB channels, compression, transition effects which I think should definitely be experimented with. Gormley To Glitch exists at the boundary between physical and digital media. In a way, the physical sculptures are becoming digital through their blocky, pixelated forms and how the act as ‘screens’. Then, through the wonder of projection, the digital is bought into the physical world as 3D objects become canvasses for the 2D digital landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Swipe effects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘enlarge’ effect (grow)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RGB distortion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compression&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pixelation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glitch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Projection mapping sequences usually have a narrative to them, things which change and evolve over a 5 or 10 minute performance for example. For this project I have been avoiding falling into the same structure with my projection mapping piece to create something different. I want it to be viewed in a similar way to how we view sculpture. Sculptures don’t move, they don’t really have a narrative to them. They just are. Sculptures exist motionless, outside of time, just waiting for us to give them a moment of our time as we view them. This is an idea which is heavily featured in Antony Gormley’s work and is why he has been such an inspiration for this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously as I am projecting video onto the sculpture it is going to change over time, there has to be a level of progression. The videos I’ve been using are 24 frames per second. That’s 24 individual ‘moments’ every second. By introducing glitch, not all of these moments are the same however. Some frame the sculpture is still, serene. Others there may be a glitch, the sculpture has been distorted, coloured introduced, chaos. Then the next it has returned to its natural state. It disrupts the usual experience and expectation of sculptural works and creates something new. But at this point it doesn’t yet create a narrative on the same level as conventional projection performances. The glitch moments are sporadic and unexpected but there isn’t a story or narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I’ll be able to test on all three models together for the first time. Up until this point there has been a singular focus with my projects as that’s all my flat would allow for. I am hoping that getting to work on the project as a whole and seeing all three models glitching together will inspire the next move. I’ve been having doubts for the past week as I haven’t seen much progression in my work and it has started to become mundane which is the last thing I want. With any luck, seeing the project as a whole will reignite my passion for it again and allow me to finish up and perfect it all in the final weeks before the deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/06/08/random-thoughts/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/06/08/random-thoughts/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Projection Progress Part 2 and 3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As I still can’t test the projection on all three sculptures together, I’m experimenting with different visuals on the lying model. At the moment I am still quite anxious and undecided as to what exactly I’d like to project and how I’d like it to look. I know that once I have all three positioned together and the projectors set up, I will be able to make better decisions about how I want it to look for the exhibiton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time has been spent generating and testing different ‘styles’ of glitch. I am trying different speeds, frequencies and other settings which change hour the glitch appears and saving them as presets so I’ll be able to use them in the future and quickly made adaptations/ improvements. I’ve included the three stages of tests so far. Video one has been posted before but the second two videos are new. They are all quite similar aesthetically becuase I have found a general style which I like and find interesting for this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uRccCRvgzS0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0LHQSjwSh2c&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ecQ6ocVWQzs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the latter half of these videos, I’ve introduced some new methods for making it appear more glitchy. This is mostly done using some audio analysis. Some of the clips use the ‘Glitch FBO’ effect in VDMX which is triggered to turn on and off based on ambient noise levels. Some also use the body part overlays which are also controlled by sound. I am using a step sequencer to toggle the opacity of the layer from 0% to 100%. The step sequence is randomly changed based on ambient noise levels too for more randomness. Part of the beauty of using these techniques is that moment will almost never be the same as there are so many variables randomly changing. The glitchy graphic loop may only be a couple of minutes long but there will be hours of unique cominations to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I showed these videos to a couple of friends for feedback and we all agree that the styles where the glitch isn’t constant work the best for actually considering it as ‘glitch’. I’m also swaying towards the ones which are at a slower pace as somehow they’re more engaging. If I do incorporate the body parts, I think they should be used sparingly so that they can still be quite surprising rather than there being too many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to be careful not to lost sight of what I set out to achieve with this project in the first place. Gormley to Glitch is about exploring our relationship with art and sculpture by disrupting conventional viewing practices and expectations. It challenges the predictable nature of physical art by contrasting it with the unpredictability of glitch art. It is meant as an exploration of the digital and glitch itself by bringing the familiarity of the digital landscape into the physical world. From the start I knew I wanted to ‘glitch’ the sculpture, not just project glitchy things on the sculpture. It is a delicate balance to actually achieve this as obviously sculptures can’t actually glitch like this. Its about creating an illusion which makes the audience question the reality of what is before them as these physical objects seemingly malfunction digitally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my biggest concerns is that the project will get boring to look at quickly. On one hand I consider how sculptures don’t do anything but people still find joy in those. I’m hoping that the random chaos of my project will be enough to draw in and maintain attention, especially as no two moments are the same. One glitch may be particularly beautiful but half a second later it’s gone, lost to the past never to be seen again. The audience will have to keep watching, keep hoping to catch more beautiful moment and savour them. This is quite different to the experience of a normal sculpture as the aesthetic appeal doesn’t change over time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/05/29/projection-progress-part-two/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/05/29/projection-progress-part-two/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Syphon Over A Network</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As my project has developed, it has become clear that it’ll be a bit too resource intensive to run everything on my laptop. For the project I am usually running VDMX to mix and control video, MadMapper for mapping the videos and a projector to display them. For the exhibition however I will need to run yet another projector and my laptop struggles as it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get the video content out of VDMX and into MadMapper, I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://syphon.v002.info&quot;&gt;syphon&lt;/a&gt; which is an open-source technology which allows you to share frames between applications. As you could share between different applications on a laptop, surely you can share between applications on different laptops? Yes, yes you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found another free application called &lt;a href=&quot;http://techlife.sg/TCPSyphon/&quot;&gt;Syphon2NDI&lt;/a&gt; which allows you to share a syphon feed over a network. This will allow me to do the video mixing and rendering in VDMX on one laptop, syphon the output over a network and receive it on another machine which will map it to two projectors. With any luck, I’ll be able to borrow a mac from the uni which I can use to power the projectors while VDMX runs on my laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/05/26/syphon-over-a-network/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/05/26/syphon-over-a-network/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Projection Progress</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past week or so, I’ve been trying to work on the content that I will be projecting onto the sculptures. In my last post I mentioned about the issues I was having about not having enough space in my house to project, so I’ve been coming up with a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a couple of weeks, I will be able to use a space at uni which is larger than my flat so I’ll be able to experiment with positioning the sculptures together. At this stage I will need to be considerate of how much space I take up in the way they’re positioned, and find positions for the projectors which provide the best coverage. This will also be an important stage as it will allow me to see how the sculptures interact, then use the projections to build on this interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then however, I can (and have been) coming up with ideas. One concern was that people who are unfamiliar with the project might not view the sculptures as people. To combat this i’d like to try merging in some glitched body parts into the projections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a video of a few tests with different degrees of glitchiness and amounts of body parts. As it was a quick test, there isnt much variety in the body parts but I do have images of more which can be used. NOTE: all the images used are of myself. As I used my own form to build the sculptures it seemed necessary to use my features too. This adds to the uncanniness of the sculpture, especially for myself as it’s so personal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uRccCRvgzS0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the begining, I’ve known that I wont be able to generate much, if any, of my content in advance. This is becuase every time I move a sculpture or a projector, the content doesn’t line up so it needs to be regenerated. However, for adding these body parts at least, I’ve created a preset in After Effects which will add certain expressions to a layer so that it will move as wanted. Each of the body parts has its position, scale, and rotation randomly changed each frame so that the result is purely chaotic. It changes the position between the bounds of the comp, the scale between 2 limits I can set (so it doesnt appear too big or small), and the rotation anywhere between 0 and 360 degrees. The result is chaotic and wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/05/18/projection-progress/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/05/18/projection-progress/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Finished Sculptures</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After a couple of weeks of cutting and gluing foamboard, the sculptures are finally finished. This now means its time to move onto the next phase of the project: developing the projections and working out how to set up the project for the exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The models started each with a base of MDF which I painted black so that it’s non-obtrusive. I then measured and cut some wood to create the armatures for the sitting and standing models. The next four photos show some progression of these armatures. They were screwed and glued together/ to the bases and an extra piece was added for stability. It also shows how the boxes were built around the armature for support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/04/armature-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wooden Armature&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/04/armature-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wooden Armature&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/04/armature-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wooden Armature&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/04/armature-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wooden Armature&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the larger boxes have extra pieces hidden inside which provide more strength and make the overall model more rigid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/04/inside-box.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wooden Armature&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-standing-sitting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wooden Armature&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-standing-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full size standing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-standing-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full size standing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-standing-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full size standing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-sitting-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full size sitting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-sitting-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full size sitting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-sitting-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full size sitting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-lying-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full size lying&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-lying-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full size lying&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-lying-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full size lying&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wooden armature inside each of the standing and sitting models provides a more strength and stability than I anticipated. They can withstand being lightly pushed and wobbled without breaking which I was quite surprised by. At them moment the lying sculptures is in four unconnected parts: The baseboard, lower body, upper body, and one arm. This is so that it can be more easily moved when needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a slight issue at the moment that the standing and sitting models don’t fit through the doorway into my bedroom where there is a little more room for testing. As such, I’ve had to try to test them in the living room which is smaller. There isn’t enough room in the living room for me to project onto the standing man or more than one model so I’ve only done a quick test with the sitting model to see how it looked. In a dark room the effect was really impressive, like, &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; impressive. The projection is bright and striking and I can’t wait to see how it looks when across three full scale models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/full-sitting-glitched.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sitting glitched&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To &lt;em&gt;just about&lt;/em&gt; cover the sitting man, I needed ~3.25m between the front of the model and the projector. This will need to be even further to cover the standing model. I am hoping that I’ll be able to mount the projectors on the ceiling and that this might help with my coverage issue, but I will need to check with the uni if this is feasible and then test it to see if it is actually an improvement. My other idea is to have the projector on its side at 90 degrees so the height is the larger dimension, but at the moment I don’t have a method of securely positioning the projector in this way so it will have to wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have come to the realisation that this isn’t going to be possible with a single projector. My current hope is to be able to do it with two projectors, but it may require three. This is my next main focus and I am currently working on procuring a space large enough for me to be able to test with the full scale models. I will also need to consider health and safety as I need to ensure the projectors and protruding cables don’t becomes hazards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this doesn’t mean I’m completely stuck in the meantime. I’m still working on my glitch projections and coming up with ideas to try. I came up a lists of goals and ideas as a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make it appear as though these physical sculptures/ objects are glitching or malfunctioning in a digital way&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Must invoke the uncanny&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blurs the boundaries between real and simulated, physical and digital&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ideas&quot;&gt;Ideas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep it simple with using just glitch effects and having parts of the sculptures seemingly disappear/ change colour/ etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The level of glitch could change based on external factors. Or there could be a number of different ‘scenes’ with different styles of glitch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use face tracking to put the viewers face on the sculptures then glitch/ distort them sculptures and faces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Distorted body parts (eyes, hands, feet, etc.) could glitch into appearance. This could perhaps be interactive in a way for example using sound monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/04/30/finished-sculptures/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/04/30/finished-sculptures/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Physical Work Begins!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Following on from my last post, I jumped in to designing my full scale models so that I can begin building them. For this, as usual, I used Cinema4D so that I can model them to the exact dimensions I need and be able to see how they will look in relation to each other and at the correct scale. With some help, I gathered some measurements of myself, to use along side my reference images so that I could make sure I was designing at the right dimensions. From here I used some of my previous models for inspiration and got to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started with the standing model by trying to work out how I wanted the torso and legs, then adding the arms in the final iteration. For my other two, the designs didn’t change much from my 1/8 scale models as these forms were really well received by my peers and I loved them too. The only adjustments were to the sizings and proportions as I changed them to better fit within my measurements. After coming up with my three forms I showed them to a few of my peers for feedback, made a few minor adjustments, then it was time to begin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In regards to my last post about materials, I’ve spoken to a local supplier for MDF and they won’t be able to cut my sizes as many of them are too small for their machine. I’ve also contacted a supplier of balsa wood blocks, and they too can’t cut the pieces I need to size due to the limitations of their machine and the sheer cost of balsa wood. The MDF suppliers suggested that I could contact a local workman they knew, but implied that it wouldn’t be cheap and would take quite a while as I needed a lot of cuts so I had to some up with another plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having had a long discussion with one of my tutors, Liam, we’ve come to the conclusion that foamboard might actually be the best option for my case. Given my incredibly limited access to tools, foamboard works well as it is easy to cut and can be assebled with hot glue as I’ve been doing for my smaller models. Another benefit is that if I were to make a mistake or it was to get broken, it should, in theory, be easy to repair as long as I have some spare materials at hand. To negate the concerns I had about the strength of the models if they were made of foam board, we decided that creating an internal structure to build around would add the strength needed - more about this later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing that I was going to use foamboard, I set about generating my cutting list. The three models in total use 61 boxes. Each box requires 6 sides. That’s a grand total of 366 pieces of foamboard I am going to need. Knowing that the foamboard is 5mm thick, I had to account for this when coming up with my measurements. I devised a wonderful naming scheme for this too. Each sculptures was named either A, B or C. Then each box was numbered, and then each of the three different pairs of sides was named a, b or c, meaning I could easily tell how they were to be constructed. So I made a list. I checked it twice. I didn’t find out who was naughty or nice, but I did luckily find a couple of mistakes so that made it worth the effort. The grand total was 114 unique dimensions. This is going to be a joy to cut…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/measurements.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Measurements&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/standing-variants.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Standing variants&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/all-three-angled.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;All three models&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/cutting-list.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cutting-list&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so, back to the internal structures. Liam and I knocked up a quick test with some scrap materials to see how it would work. The results of this are pictured below. In short I am going to have a large base board, a few up-rights, and a few blocks to just make it sturdy. I think I will give each sculpture the same sized base board so that it creates congruence between the models and visually makes them more linked. For the standing model, the support system will be simple, just a base and an upright. The lying is even simpler, just a board which I can glue the model onto. Finally the sitting which is the one we mocked up. For this I’m going to use a weird Tetris block shape and then I will build the foamboard blocks around this structure to bury it inside. This structure will definitely give it the extra strength needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dad suggested a way of strengthening the foamboard boxes too. I am going to the edges together, and when that dries I will run glue up the inside seam to make them more rigid. Also for certain, larger boxes I can add an internal support out of foamboard so that there is some more strength in the middle and not just around the edges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the successful test, I went away and mocked up the supported in Cinema4D so I could better visualise the dimensions I need and how they will go in the sculptures. For both the sitting and standing sculptures, I am planning on running the supports up the left legs as I can’t run them up the centre due to gaps in the design. Luckily, due to the disjointed, abstracted form, there is some leeway with how the boxes are placed, therefore I can made adjustments around the internal structure if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have ordered some foamboard which is going to be delivered next week, and I am planning on visiting B&amp;amp;Q to buy the wood needed for the support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/support-test-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Support test&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/support-test-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Support test&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/support-test-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Support test&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/standing-with-support-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Standing model&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/standing-with-support.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Standing model&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/sitting-with-support.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sitting model&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/sitting-with-support-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sitting model&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/2017/03/lying-with-support.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lying model&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/03/26/physical-works-begin/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/03/26/physical-works-begin/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Progress Update - Physical Work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I came up with my concept of the uncanny and presented it to my tutor and peers to get some feedback. Luckily the idea went down a treat which means I can sleep a bit easier at night and not stress about coming up with a concept. This part has been the most challenging so far as we haven’t been trained in art or art history so it is quite far out of the norm of what we’re used to. However the next challenge, will probably be even harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I have my direction, I can begin with the arduous task of designing and somehow actually building the sculptures. Up to this point, I’ve just been building scale models out of foamboard. However from working with foamboard, I’m having doubts about its strength when it comes to full size models. Well, I think  it would be suitable for the lying sculpture, and perhaps even the sitting sculpture but for the standing I don’t think it will work as the foamboard isn’t strong enough, and I’d like all three (preferably) to be made of the same material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sculptures are large, and there’s three of them, therefore I need to find a material which is strong but low cost. I also really need something that is easy to work with as I am quite poorly equipped for building physical works at the moment. I have spoken to the technicians in the sci-tech workshops however they’re unable to provide me any space or access to the tools as they’re needed for people on scitech courses (which is entirely reasonable). This leaves me in quite a difficult position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a few ideas so far on how I could do it. The best two at the moment are using either MDF or balsa wood. MDF would work well as it is low cost and easy to work with (if I had the tools). The biggest issue here is getting the MDF cut to size as I am going to need A LOT of rectangle cut. Even then I would need to assemble and clamp them to make the blocks needed. The other alternative is balsa as it is very lightweight, relatively low cost (not as low as MDF) and easy to work with. I have found a few places online which sell it in blocks. I could therefore design the sculptures around the dimensions of these blocks and do it this way. But this will definitely be far more expensive, and even I may need to resize the blocks, make them smaller, or combine them to make them larger and will need to assemble them to make the models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another of the many issues is transportation. These are going to be big, Kurt-sized models and not the easiest things to transport. in my assembly I will need to take this into consideration and perhaps build in a way to take them apart and assemble them on site. This is something I will need to think more about later but it is definitely worth considering now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may have guessed, this is going to be the most difficult part of this project and has been concerning me the most. when working with the digital we take for granted the ability to constantly edit and change things - not a luxury had when working with physical objects. I am going to need to check and double check my dimensions when cutting the material as I can’t afford to make mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/03/20/progress-update/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kurtstubbings.com/blog/graduate%20project/2017/03/20/progress-update/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Graduate Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
